<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Adam Gastineau's Writings</title><link>https://writings.agg.im/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Adam Gastineau's Writings</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 20:27:09 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://writings.agg.im/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hacking the Humane Ai Pin</title><link>https://writings.agg.im/posts/hacking_ai_pin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 20:27:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://writings.agg.im/posts/hacking_ai_pin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="#first-access"&gt;Skip to the technical stuff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="shutdown-announcement"&gt;Shutdown announcement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On February 18, 2025, Humane announced it would be shutting down all services for the always online Humane Ai Pin in ten days, &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20250219012718/https://humane.com/media/humane-hp"&gt;following a sale to HP&lt;/a&gt;. I had been vaguely aware of the Ai Pin, definitely more so than the average tech person, as I have a close friend who was one of the earliest adopters and eventually joined the Humane team to actively work on the device, but I ultimately knew little about them. I did know that they were small, ran Android, had good industrial design, and had a cool laser. I also have drempt of a personal, local always listening device since I was a young teenager. I was a little more confident in my ability to help shape a niche device&amp;rsquo;s ecosystem after my experiences driving the Analogue Pocket&amp;rsquo;s growth, so I decided to go looking for disgruntled users looking to sell their devices.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>FPGA Composite NTSC Video</title><link>https://writings.agg.im/posts/fpga-compositevideo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 11:13:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://writings.agg.im/posts/fpga-compositevideo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This was originally published at &lt;a href="https://github.com/agg23/fpga-compositevideo"&gt;https://github.com/agg23/fpga-compositevideo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="fpga-composite-ntsc-video"&gt;FPGA Composite NTSC Video&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src="https://writings.agg.im/writings/external/fpga-compositevideo/assets/nesdisplay.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project records an experiment I made to attempt to output composite video via a FPGA; direct driving IO pins and without any complicated hardware. This implementation supports up to 6 levels of greys, and only requires wires and 3 resistors to build the psuedo-DAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="getting-started"&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out on this project with a new devboard, the &lt;a href="https://wiki.sipeed.com/hardware/en/tang/Tang-Nano-9K/Nano-9K.html"&gt;Tang Nano 9k&lt;/a&gt;. This gave me fast iteration times, and at least at the beginning, the joy of using a OSS toolchain. However, I quickly had to abandon the OSS toolchain due to lack of proper RAM support.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>